時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
천공환, 천지환과 이도류를 자기 것으로 만든 무사시는 이천일류의 완성을 노린다.
(Niten'ichi-ryu: 二天一流, Musashi-ryu; the art of using two swords)
After taking Tenkūmaru and Tenchimaru into his hands, Musashi looks to perfect his Nitenichiryu.
대도둑 고에몬도의 거대 지네에 고통받는 무사시 일행.
Everyone suffered from the huge centipede of Goemondo, a grand thief.
그러나 그 전투 중에서 무사시는 결국 이천일류를 개안하였다.
But during that fight, Musashi finally opened his eyes towards Nitenichiryu.
(I am unsure with some proper nouns used in this episode, so they might be wrong)
누에가 우는 밤은 무섭소
The Night that
Nue Cries is Scary
멈추시오, 코지로!
Stop, Kojirō!
자, 코지로, 승부를 보시오!
Hey, Kojirō, have a match with me!
작작 좀 해라, 무사시! 센히메 님이 기막혀하고 있지 않냐!
That's enough, Musashi! Senhime is astonished of you!
기막혀할 사람은 기막혀하겠지만 난 진심이오!
Someone might be looking down on me, but I am dead serious-dasu!
진검을 뽑아들었으니 진검승부의 마음가짐을 하고 있다는 건 잘 알겠어.
I know that you're going to be dead if you're dead serious.
서투른 농담은 하지 마시오...
You shouldn't make bad jokes-dasu...
서투르다고?!
It was bad?!
무사시는 쉽게 발끈하니까 신경쓰지 않는 편이 좋습니다.
Musashi gets angry so easily, so you shouldn't give attention to him.
그렇소! 난 쉽게 발끈하오! 자, 코지로, 승부를 보시오!
That's right! I get angry easily-dasu! Now, Kojirō, face me-dasu!
이천일류로 훌륭하게 츠바메가에시를 물려내 보이겠소!
I will defeat Tsubamegaeshi with Nitenichiryu!
알았어, 알았어! 이천이류는 대단해. 그렇지만, 무사시, 이 여행의 목적은...
Sure, I get that Nitenichiryu is great. But Musashi, what is the purpose of this trip?
센짱을 지키는 것이오.
To protect Sen-chan-dasu.
그래. 그러니까 여행이 끝나면 바로 상대해 줄 테니까.
Right. So just know that I'll going to face you as soon as the trip is over.
여행은 안 끝나오...
The trip will never end-dasu.
-어?
-왜?
-Huh?
-Why?
센짱은 영원히 새신랑 못 찾으니까이오!
Sen-chan will never find a new husband-dasu!
미안하오!
I'm sorry-dasu!
멈춰라, 무사시!
Stop right there, Musashi!
멈춰!
Stop!
-그렇게 난폭하면 죽어도 새신랑 못 찾소!
-무사시!
-If you act violent like that, you'll never get a husband-dasu!
-Musashi!
센다이 마을은 아직이오...
Are we at Sendai village yet-dasu?
무사시가 멍청한 짓만 골라서 하니까 늦어졌잖냐.
We're late only because you did all the stupid things possible, Musashi.
센다이 마을이야!
I see Sendai village!
어?
Huh?
저것이 센다이 성이오!
That must be Sendai village-dasu!
밥밥밥~
Food, food, food!
어이, 무사시!
Hey, Musashi!
정말...
Damn...
밥이 날 부르고 있소...
Food is calling me-dasu!
센짱, 뒤이오!
Sen-chan, on your back-dasu!
대체 누구시오! 갑자기 덤벼들다니 비겁하오!
Who is it-dasu?! It is cowardly to pounce out of nowhere-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
무사시 아니냐!
Aren't you Musashi?
바이켄!
Baiken!
오랜만이오!
Long time no see-dasu!
이야, 반갑네! 그 말은?
Glad to see you! And that would mean...
모두 칼을 거두어라!
Everyone, take your swords in!
-바이켄 님!
-바이켄!
-Mr. Baiken!
-Baiken!
모른다고 하지는 않겠습니다. 큰 무례를 저질렀습니다. 용서해 주십시오, 센히메 님!
I'm not going to make excuses. I was very rude to you. Please forgive me, princess!
센짱이야! 센짱!
Sen-chan, that is! Sen-chan!
아, 센짱입니까...
Oh, Sen-chan, is it?
그보다도, 바이켄은 왜 여기에?
More importantly, why is Baiken here?
이 센다이 다테 가 아래 결국 취직했다!
I finally got a job under Date clan!
정말이오?!
Really-dasu?!
축하해. 잘 됐네.
Congratulations. That's good to know.
그건 축하드립니다.
Congratulations from me.
고맙수!
Thank you!
근데 왜 우리에게 덤벼들었소?
But why did you attack us?
다테 가를 쳐부수려고 하는 악인이 오니까. 그걸 막으라는 임무를 얻었다.
I was assigned a mission to stop bad people from destroying Date clan.
-누구에게이오?
-다테 아키노카미라는 성주 다테 카메치오의 숙부다.
-From who-dasu?
-Date Akinokami, the uncle of the feudal lord, Kamechio.
다테 아키노카미?
Date Akinokami?
그래도 틀렸네! 자, 어쨌든 우리 집으로 와라! 환영한다!
But I was wrong! Just come to my home for now! I welcome all of you!
화, 환영이라면 밥도 나오오?
W- welcome? Will you give us food-dasu?!
물론이지!
Of course!
야호! 밥이다! 밥 이 다! 밥이다!
Yay! Food! F o o d! Food!
적당히 해라! 꼴불견이다!
Stop it! How unsightly of you!
꼴불견이랬지!
I told you that you are being unsightly!
칫, 아는 사이였군.
Tch, they knew each other?
잠깐, 무사시, 코지로 실력을 이 기회에 이용할 수도 있겠구나.
Oh, maybe I might be able to use Musashi and Kojirō's technique for my own good.
이, 이게 바이켄의 집이오?
I- is this Baiken's house-dasu?
거대한 집이오!
What a big house-dasu!
아니, 그럴 정도까진 아니다!
Well, it's not really that big!
어서 오세요.
Welcome back.
대단하오...
Awesome-dasu...
지금 돌아왔다!
I'm back!
형님! 어서오세요.
Brother, welcome back!
-오세요!
-Welcome!
어, 잇켄, 니켄, 오하루! 건강해 보이오!
Hey, Ikken, Niken, and Oharu! You look well-dasu!
-어! 무사시다!
-무사시다!
-It's Musashi!
-Musashi!
이건이건 무사시 님! 오랜만입니다.
This must be Mr. Musashi! It's been a long time!
어라, 무슨 일이오, 잇켄...
Huh, what's up-dasu, Ikken?
잇켄 형은 바이켄 형이 충실한 무사가 되었으니까 모두 격식을 높이 차리래.
Ikken asks us to be formal, since our brother Baiken became a proper warrior!
이야, 잇켄 대단하오!
How praiseworthy of Ikken-dasu!
호화, 호화! 호화롭소!
Splendid, splendid, splendid-dasu!
사양말고 막 먹으쇼!
Eat as much as you want!
말 안 해도 먹소!
You don't have to tell me that-dasu!
닛켄! 무사의 집에 사는 자는 무사답게!
Nikken! Act like a warrior, since you live in a warrior's house!
좋은 말 하는구나!
Well said!
누군가 씨하고는 크게 다르네.
That's very different from Mr. Someone.
응? 뭐라 했소?
Huh? Did you say something?
그래도, 바이켄도 출세했소!
Anyway, Baiken, you've succeeded in your life-dasu!
내가 여기 살게 해 준 다테 아키노카미 덕이다!
It's all thanks to Date Akinokami, for letting me live here!
바이켄 님의 실력이 보였던 것일까요.
He must have seen through Mr. Baiken's abilities.
물론이오.
Of course he did-dasu.
실은 성주 다테 카메치오에게 요괴 누에가 달려들어서 말이야.
The truth is, Nue, a monster, is giving pain to Date Kamechio, the feudal lord.
누에?
Nue?
누에라는 것은 먼 옛날에 한밤중에 신전 위에 펄쩍 뛰어 올라 당시의 궁궐에 매달리는 괴물로,
Nue is a monster from a long time ago that jumps up onto a shrine in midnight and clings to royal palace of the time.
미나모토의 요리마사가 쏘아 잡아 보니
When Minamoto's Yorimasa took it down with his arrow,
그 누에는 머리는 원숭이, 몸통은 너구리, 꼬리는 뱀, 손발은 호랑이였다고 하는 존재이다.
he found that Nue had a head of a monkey, a body of a raccoon, a tail of a snake, and hands and feet of a tiger.
-손님을 데려왔습니다.
-들어와라.
-I brought all the people.
-Come in.
잘 오셨구려. 내가 다테 아키노카미다.
Welcome. I am Date Akinokami.
-나는...
-무사시 님, 코지로 님에 센 님.
-I'm...
-Mr. Musashi, Mr. Kojirō, and Ms. Sen.
바이켄에게서 들었습니다. 두 분 다 일류 무예가라고.
I heard from Baiken. Both of you are top-class martial artists.
그런데도 어젯밤은 틀린 정보를 믿고 습격하고 해서 실례했습니다.
I sincerely apologize for making them attack you based on a false information.
오해를 풀었으면 그걸로 좋소.
It's alright since you know that it was a misunderstanding-dasu.
게다가 또 이번에는 누에 퇴치를 도와주신다니.
And now you're saying that you'll help us get rid of Nue...
그렇소!
Right!
지금까지 요괴를 퇴치한 일이 있는 것 같구려.
It seems that they have prior experiences of eliminating monsters.
그건 든든하네.
That's reassuring.
누에에게 시달리고 있는 녀석...
She's suffering from Nue...
젊지만 명군이라고 불렸던 성주, 카메치오는 쭉 몸져 누워 앓는 소리만 할 뿐.
Kamechi was called as a wise ruler for a young person, but now she has been bedridden for a while.
누에는 매일 밤 나오나요?
Does that Nue come out every night?
아니, 매일 밤이라고 할 것까지는 없지만,
No, I wouldn't say every night,
오늘 밤에 나타날 것 같은 기미가...
but still it seems that it's gonna appear today's night.
이건 너무하네요. 성주가 이 상태여서야는 누가 정치를 하고 계시나요?
This really is bad. Who is governing then, when the lord is like this?
신하 총괄인 하라다 카이노스케 님이다.
Harada Kainosuke, the chief retainer.
하라다 카이노스케...
Harada Kainosuke...
모두들! 수고했다.
Everyone! Thank you for your efforts.
신하 총괄인 하라다 카이노스케 님이다.
He's Harada Kainosuke, the chief retainer.
이 사람들에 대해서 말해 주자면, 하라다 님은 누에 퇴치의 총지휘관이다.
I'll tell you about him. Mr. Harada is the commander in chief of exterminating Nue.
코지로 님은 어느 분이신가.
I wonder who is Mr. Kojirō.
예, 저입니다.
Yessir, that is me.
오, 그 쪽의 츠바메가에시의 대단함은 들어서 안다!
Oh, I heard about the excellence of Tsubamegaeshi of yours!
든든하니 크게 기쁘군! 의지하겠어!
That definitely is reassuring and makes me happy! I'll be relying on you!
예.
Thank you.
어, 저, 제 이천일류도 유명하고...
Uh, how about my Nitenichiryu, the world-famous technique?
이천일류? 몰라.
Nitenichiryu? Never heard of it.
그럼 모두들, 나머지는 잘 부탁한다!
Then everyone, please do your best!
이천일류를 모르다니 실례이오!
It's a discourtesy to not know about Nitenichiryu-dasu!
큰일이다!
This is bad!
날아올 거야!
It's going to fly to here!
무슨 일이야?
What's up now?
요괴가 다가오는 기운이 드오.
It seems that a monster is approaching-dasu.
그것도 천장 방향에서이오.
From the roof side.
숨통이 끊겼나?!
Did you get it?
연기를 마시지 마라!
Do not inhale the smoke!
위기에 처한 모두들. 과연 누에는 어떤 요괴인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Everyone are now in trouble. What kind of monster is Nue? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
저게 누에이오....
So that must be Nue-dasu...
카메치오를 세뇌하려 하고 있어.
It is trying to brainwash Kamechi.
도망쳐버렸소!
It ran away-dasu!
Go out and chase! It must have ran away towards the roof!
밖으로 쫒아! 녀석은 지붕 쪽으로 달아났을 게 틀림없어!
좋아!
Right!
저기이오!
There-dasu!
괜찮아?
Will it be okay?
맡겨만 두시오!
Leave it to me-dasu!
무사시!
Musashi!
아, 도망치겠어!
It's gonna run away!
젠장!
Damn it!
젠장, 눈앞에서 놓친 것이오!
Damn, I was so close!
누에의 피이오!
Nue's blood-dasu!
기분 나빠!
That's disgusting!
난간에 붙어 있었소.
It was sticking to railing-dasu...
그렇군! 잘 하면 누에가 어디로 갔는지 찾아낼 수 있을지도 모르겠어.
I see! We might be able to find out where did that Nue disappear to.
역시 코지로! 누에 피를 쫒아가다니!
Good idea, Kojirō, for following Nue's blood traces!
그래도 계속 이어져 있다니, 바이켄의 쿠사리가마가 꽤나 깊은 상처를 남겼나 보오.
Anyway, Baiken's Kusarigama surely did much damage to it since it's all over the road-dasu!
잘 밝혀낼 수 있으면 좋겠다만...
I hope we can find this out properly...
분명 저 문 안으로 들어간 것 같소.
It must've went inside that door-dasu...
그래도 하늘에서 내려온 것이 굳이 문 안으로 들어가다니...
But why would something that came from the sky go through a door?
어쨌든 한번 가 보오!
Anyway let's go find it out-dasu!
하라다?
Harada?
하라다라니, 그 신하 총괄?
Harada? That chief retainer?
하라다 카이노스케의 집이오?
Is this Harada Kainosuke's house-dasu?
이게 대체 무슨 일이냐.
What is going on here?
코지로는 거대한 의혹을 품었다. 그러나, 과연 그 의혹은 무엇인가?
Kojirō harbored a big suspicion. What could be his suspicion?
뭐라? 반역자로 할복시키러 왔다고?
What? You're here to make me make me disembowel?!
요괴 누에를 써서 영주를 농해 미치게 하고, 원하는 대로 부린 죄.
You are charged for toying with the feudal lord and making her go crazy using a monster named Nue!
가만 두었으면 영주를 살해하고 다테 가를 점령하러 한 대악인 놈!
You are a criminal who might even tried to murder the lord and take control of the whole Date clan!
그건 다테 아키노카미, 네 쪽인줄 알아라!
That is you, Date Akinokami!
멍청한 놈. 증거가 분명히 있다.
You fool! I have a definite evidence.
증거? 어디에?
Evidence, eh? Where?
이 집의 어딘가에 누에가 숨어 있다. 그것이 제일의 증거다!
Nue is hiding inside this house somewhere. That is the definitive evidence!
-누에 따위 없다.
-그럼 조사해 보겠어.
-There is no Nue here.
-Then let me search.
좋다! 대신, 찾지 못할 때는, 그 쪽이 할복을 해야 할 테이다!
Agreed! But if you fail to find one, I'll have you disemboweled instead!
좋다.
Sure.
이랴!
Charge!
저곳이오!
There-dasu!
저, 저게 무슨!
H- how could it be?!
하라다 카이노스케, 이래도 아직도 시치미뗄 생각인가?
Harada Kainosuke, are you still going to assume innocence?
이, 이건 누군가의 음모다. 난 몰라!
T- this is someone's conspiracy! I know nothing about this!
이 정의롭지 못한 놈!
You outrageous bastard!
이제 상관없다! 하라다 카이노스케를 베어버려라!
Nothing matters now! Cut Harada Kainosuke!
코지로!
Kojirō!
눈이 뒤집혔나, 코지로.
Did you lose your mind, Kojirō?!
진짜 대악인은 다테 아키노카미, 네놈이다!
The real criminal is Date Akinokami, you!
뭐, 뭣이오?
W- what-dasu?!
코지로! 쓸데없는 소리 집어치우지 않으면 그냥은 안 넘어간다!
Kojirō! Forget about whatever's in your mind, or I'm not letting this pass!
이 짚신은 아키노카미, 당신 것이지요.
Is this straw sandal yours, Akinokami?
그, 그렇긴 한데.
Right, but?
이 녹색 얼룩을 뭐라 할 셈인가?
How are you going to explain this green stain?
그, 그건 누에의 피.
T- that must be Nue's blood.
왜 아키노카미의 짚신에?!
Why would it be on Akinokami's sandal?!
이것은 피가 아니라 녹색 물감이다.
This is not a blood, but is a green dye.
어떻게 된 일이오?
What's going on here-dasu?
아키노카미는 그 밤에 자신도 쓰러진 체를 하면서도 우리보다도 앞질러서 녹색 물감을 들고 갔다.
Akinokami acted as if he collapsed in that night, but actually, he ran in front of us with green dye.
그리고 누에를 이 곳의 천장 속에 몰래 넣었다. 그것도 이것도 전부 죄를 하라다 님께 뒤집어씌우기 위해!
And he put Nue into the roof of this room. All is to blame Harada for all of his crimes!
이 무슨 비열한!
How nasty of you!
어라, 코지로 머리 좋소...
Hey, Kojirō's with a good brain...
들킨 이상 어쩔 수 없군!
It can't be helped, since you found out!
누에여! 해라! 말살해 버려라!
Nue! Do it! Kill everyone!
멈추시오!
Stop!
너는...
Who are you?
오랜만이군, 무사시.
It's been a while, Musashi.
뭣이오? 난 당신 따위 모르오!
What? I don't know you-dasu!
넌 오니히메!
You're Onihime!
그렇군. 전부 네 계략이었구나.
I see. Everything was your trickery.
이제야 깨달았나, 무사시, 코지로! 너희들 생명도 이 김에 가져가겠다!
Did you realize it now? Musashi and Kojirō, I will take your lives with me using this chance!
아키노카미! 각오하쇼!
Akinokami! Prepare yourself!
에잇, 이렇게 된 바에는...
This leaves me no choice!
아키노카미! 각오해라!
Akinokami! Prepare yourself!
이천일류 섬광검!
Nitenichiryu: Flash Sword!
무사시 놈, 기억해 둬라!
Musashi, you bastard! Remember this!
나, 멋지오!
Ain't I cool-dasu?
우리 다테 가의 위기를 구해 주셔서, 참말로 감사했습니다.
Thank you for rescuing our Date clan from a crisis.
아니, 우리야말로 하라다 씨를 의심해서 미안하오!
No, but instead, we are sorry for suspecting Mr. Harada-dasu!
이 소동이 제너럴 이에야스 귀에 들어가면 상속 문제로 내분이 일어난 것으로 취급되어 재산을 몰수당할 게야.
When General Ieyasu hears about this, he'll treat this as an internal
conflict over heirship, and all the property will be confiscated.
그 걱정은 할 필요 없습니다.
You don't have to worry about that.
제 할아버지께 진실을 전달해 드리겠습니다.
I'll tell my grandfather about the truth.
할아버지?
Grandfather?
여기 있는 날 누구로 아는가! 이에야스의 손녀, 센히메다!
Who do you think I am? I am Senhime, the granddaughter of Ieyasu!
그, 그런!
N- no way!
하라다 카이노스케 님, 다테 가는 무사합니다. 안심하세요.
Mr. Harada Kainosuke, Date clan will be safe. You can relieve.
예! 황송해 몸둘 바를 모르겠습니다!
Yessir! I am very thankful for this!
하라다 씨가 머물게 해 주겠다고 했는데도 정말 여행길을 떠날 것이오?
Are you really going to leave, when Mr. Harada is offering you to stay-dasu?
이번 일로 아직 수행이 부족하다는 걸 깨달았다.
I realized that I lack discipline, by what happened today.
역시 형이나 우리에겐 성에서 근무하는 건 안 맞아!
Neither brother nor us doesn't go with working in a castle!
모두더욱 고생하게 될 거야!
You're all going to have a difficult time!
뭐, 익숙하잖아?
Well, aren't we all used to it?
뭔가 기분 좋아지는 것을 가슴에 품으며 무사시 일행은 여행을 계속한다.
The felt good, but they did not know what it was about. They continued to travel...
그러나 다음의 무서운 마의 손은 곧장 앞에 다가오고 있었다.
However, their next frightening evil hand was right in front of them.
그러나, 기세가 꺾이면 안 된다, 무사시. 내일(明日)이라는 글자는 밝은(明るい) 날(日)이라고 쓴다.
But don't be dispirited, Musashi!
To write Tomorrow(明日), you write Bright(明るい) and Day(日) in a row.
カラのポケットに　ツキが
飛び込むことも　あるさ
おっきな声で　笑えば
あしたには　朝が来る
無くすものなんか　何もないさ
やっちゃえ！イケイケ！
手ぶらは　強いぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
人生　てなもんさ　チャンスが　ほら
しっぽを振って　追ってくるぜ
てなもんだ　のーてんきに行こう
未来も　てなもんさ　あしたが　ほら
両手ひろげて　笑ってるぜ
비밀의 금 광산에 대해 알게 된 산타(三太)의 아버지와 마을 사람들을 구출하러 간 우리는 거대한 흙인형 전사하고 만났소.
We went to rescue Santa(三太)'s father and the villagers who found out about the secret gold mountain,
and we faced a giant clay warrior-dasu.
이 녀석, 거대할 뿐이라 생각했더니, 베어도 베어도 원래대로!
I thought this was just a huge figure, but even if I cut, it just keeps regenerating-dasu!
내 이도류로도 이길 수가 없소.
I can't defeat this with my dual blade skills!
이 무슨, 흙인형을 조종하고 있던 자는 전의 슈텐타이가.
What the?! That Shutentiger from before is controlling that clay warrior!
다음 이야기! 슈텐, 대폭발이오
Next story! Shuten Explodes!
질풍노도의 선공권이오!
It's a stormy Senpūken-dasu!
다음 이야기
슈텐, 대폭발이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Shuten Explodes
Look forwards for it!